Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Allen Thomas papers, 1984-2000 and undated RL.11480
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Allen Thomas papers
1984-2000 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11480
2.0 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. The London Office first opened in 1899. Allen Thomas was an executive who served as Chairman of JWT's London Office as well as JWT Europe. Collection includes correspondence, client files, meeting minutes, research reports, presentations and other printed materials. Companies represented include De Beers, Nestle and Unilever. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General Files; Accounts.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. The London Office first opened in 1899.
Allen Thomas began at JWT London as a copywriter in 1966; Creative Director, Davidson Pearce Agency, 1978-1982; Creative Director, JWT London, 1982; Chairman JWT London 1988; Chairman and Chief Creative Officer, JWT Europe 1991.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Allen Thomas papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2008.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company London Office records; J. Walter Thompson Company International Offices records; J. Walter Thompson Company International Advertisements.
Collection Overview
Collection includes correspondence, client files, meeting minutes, research reports, presentations and other printed materials. Companies represented include De Beers, Nestle and Unilever. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising -- Great Britain; Advertising -- Great Britain -- History; Advertising agencies -- Great Britain; Advertising agencies -- Great Britain -- History; Advertising executives -- Great Britain; Advertising agencies -- Management; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; De Beers Consolidated Mines; Nestlé Company; Unilever (Firm)
- General Files, 1984-1995 and undated; 1
  - Chairman's Strategy Group meetings, 1991-1993; 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Creative Exchange, 1992-1993; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Focus Television Production System, undated (Box 1)
  - Global Business Partnerships, 1995 (Box 1)
  - JWT 3-Year Plan, 1994-1995 (Box 1)
  - Martin Sorrell, 1989-1993 (Box 1)
  - New Business--Banks, 1990 (Box 1)
  - New Business--Lloyd's Bank, 1990 (Box 1)
  - New Business--Project Firecracker: Who Knows Who, 1990 (Box 1)
  - New Business--TNT, IBM, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Offices and Subsidiaries--Amsterdam, 1991-1995; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Offices and Subsidiaries--Detroit, 1993-1994 (Box 2)
  - Offices and Subsidiaries--Europe, 1990-1994 and undated; 7 folders (Box 2)
  - Offices and Subsidiaries--New York, 1990-1994; 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Offices and Subsidiaries--PPGH/JWT, 1984-1989 and undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Offices and Subsidiaries--PPGH/Moussault, 1984-1987 (Box 2)
  - Offices and Subsidiaries--TMI, 1995; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Projects, 1992-1995 (Box 3)
  - Public relations and press, 1992-1994 (Box 3)
  - Strategy groups, 1991-1992 (Box 3)
  - WPP, 1987 (Box 3)
- Accounts, 1991-2000; 2
  - British Midlands, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Compari, 1993 (Box 3)
  - De Beers, 1991-1996; 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Kellogg's, 1992-1994 (Box 3)
  - Kodak, 1991-1993 (Box 3)
  - Lever, 1991-1992 (Box 3)
  - Lever/Lipton Chicken Tonight, 1992-1994; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Nestle, 1991-1994 (Box 3)
  - Nestle/JWT annual review, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Smirnoff, 1992 (Box 4)
  - Unilever, 1991-1994; 3 folders (Box 4)